Daniel Soyer. ILGWU Heritage Project. 6036/076 OH
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Daniel Soyer. ILGWU Heritage Project.
2008-2009
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Heritage Project
Soyer, Daniel
6036/076 OH
0.72 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.
This collection contains oral history transcripts conducted by Daniel Soyer for the ILGWU Heritage Project.
6855749
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 29, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Scope and Contents
The ILGWU Heritage Project aims to document the history of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union by collecting oral histories from retired union officers and staff. Daniel Soyer, a professor in the History Department at Fordham University, conducted the interviews in 2008 and 2009. This collection contains the audio recordings and the transcripts from the oral histories as well as providing biographical information on the subjects and an abstract of the interview. Those interviewed include: Henry Foner, Barbara Laufman, Emanuel Leventhal, Walter Mankoff, Ralph Reuter, Saul Rosen, Beverly Shulman, Irwin Solomon, David Wells, and Max Zimny. Many of the interviews have various levels of restrictions for use.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780 OH: ILGWU. Oral History 5780/110 OHT: ILGWU. Oral histories
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Foner, Henry.; Laufman, Barbara.; Leventhal, Emanuel.; Mankoff, Walter.; Reuter, Ralph.; Rosen, Saul.; Shulman, Beverly.; Solomon, Irwin.; Soyer, Daniel.; Wells, David.; Zimny, Max.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- Computer files.
6855749
- Henry Foner, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Interviewed on June 10, 2009. 37 pages.
- Barbara Laufman, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Interviewed on December 18, 2008. 40 pages.
- Emanuel Leventhal, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Interviewed on March 13, 2009. 62 pages.
- Walter Mankoff, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Interviewed on June 3, 2009. 47 pages.
- Ralph Reuter, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Interviewed on March 4, 2009. 51 pages.
- Saul Rosen, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Interviewed on June 12, 2009. 39 pages.
- Beverly Shulman, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Interviewed on July 6, 2009. 38 pages.
- Irwin Solomon, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Interviewed on August 12, 2009. 35 pages.
- David Wells, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Interviewed on April 1, 2009. 40 pages.
- Max Zimny, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Interviewed on May 22, 2009. 78 pages.